John Nguyen

Software Engineer nguyentuanj@gmail.com 425-749-6695

Website

ABOUT

Github

I'm a Software Engineer with 3 years of experience. Currently, I'm contributing to building SAAS for multiple large retail clients. I emphasize building efficient and sustainable software. I also value establishing positive relationships with coworkers and clients. I specialize in React and Python but am open to expanding my expertise in other domains.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Boston Consulting Group (BCG)

Feb 2022 - Present

- Built complex cross-browser functionalities that retrieve, compute, and save user data.
- •• Performed code reviews for dozens of engineers to ensure code meets infrastructure and code guidelines.
- Collaborated with other software engineers to implement and enhance complex features.
- Developed efficient and maintainable software to meet business objectives.

Software Engineer

Fast Enterprises

Aug 2019 - Oct 2020

- Collaborated with a 3rd party vendor to implement a system to process taxpayer data.
- Implemented an electronic filing service that processes tax returns.
- Proficiently troubleshoot simple and complex technological issues for different assigned projects.

Data Analyst

Fantasy Moguls

May 2018 - Jan 2019

- Analyze user spending habits and produced multiple reports to reveal popular spending habits.
- > Built an automated process to retrieve the most up to date rosters.
- Retrieved professional athletes stats and computed their impact in game simulations.

App Developer

University of Montana School of Business Sep 2019 – Oct 2020

- Designed and developed a Android app that collects student data through a friendly UI.
- •• Led multiple scrum meetings to stay aligned with management.

SKILLS

React	NodeJs
Python	Firebase
JavaScript	MongoDB
React Native	Django
Java	FastAPI

EDUCATION

University of Montana

Management Information Systems Aug 2013 - Jan 2018

PROJECTS

Softlete

Try it View Code

Aug 2021 - Present

A full stack **React** application

React MongoDB

NodeJs Firebase

React Native

Habts

Try it View Code

Feb 2021 - Present

A full stack **React** application

React Firebase
React Native

See More

AFFILIATIONS

Collegiate Athlete

University of Montana Football Team

Aug 2013 – Dec 2017

Professional Athlete & Coach

MSA Tigers Football Team (Cairo, Egypt)

Feb 2019 – May 2019

Technology Specialist

People's Voice On Climate Jan 2021 - Present

Sports Performance Trainer

Freelance

Spring 2021 - Present